MAHMOUD MOHAMED

FRONT-END DEVELOPER (REACT - NEXT)

Email: Mahmoudabbamalik@GMAIL.COM **Linkedin: Mahmoud Mohamed**

Portfolio:devmahmoud.tech Github:Eng1mahmoud

Address: Cairo - Egypt

Military service: performed Number: +201201453941/+201125948712

Summary

Specialized in implementing the front-end interfaces for websites that customers use to purchase products or subscribe to services. I develop the interface in an attractive way that helps customers explore the website easily and without complexity and provides a smooth transition between each section and another. I provide a very fast and accurate user experience, and I also provide distinguished performance of the site for its basic function and display the brand in a homogeneous manner that helps the customer place his trust in the customer.

Technical & soft skills

HTML/HTML5

Next.js

Material UI

Agile methodologies

Communication skills

CSS/CSS3/SASS

TypeScript

Tailwind CSS

React Query

Team work

JavaScript/ES6

Node.js

Bootstrap

Nodemailer

creativity and innovation

Redux

· Express.js

Axios

Work under stress

· Planning and organizing

• React.js

MongoDB

Formik

Solving problems

Quick learning

EDUCATION

SOHAG UNIVERSITY

- Bachelor's Degree in Computers and Artificial Intelligence.
- · Department: information technology
- Grade:very good
- Graduation year:2023

GRADUATION PROJECT:

(4/2023 - 6/2023)

BOOKING

- Built a ticket booking website using React. js, MUI, Node. js, Express. js, and MongoDB.
- · Managed the entire development process independently.
- Developed a ticket booking website using the MERN stack.
- Live project

E-COMMERCE WEBSITE

(4/2024-6/2024)

- Created an e-commerce platform for selling various products.
- Integrated Stripe for payment processing and Cloudinary for image hosting.
- Live project

Professional experience

FRONT-END DEVELOPER AT STARTUP COMPANY FROM NOV.2024 TILL NOW.

- Convert Fig-ma designs to web applications.
- Integrate with back-end API s.
- Enhance web performance and maintain clean code.
- Find solutions for front-end problems
- Writing reusable code Developing components and interfaces that can be reused in various projects.
- Integrate data and services through APIs to ensure seamless interaction with servers
- Work with UX/UI designers and software development teams to achieve desired designs and functionality.

WEB DEVELOPER AT COD SOFT FROM SEP.2023 TO OCT.2024.

- Translated UI/UX designs into code using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React. --Developed databas
- Developed databases using MongoDB and created APIs to connect with the front end.
- Build and maintain servers and databases using languages such as Node.js.
- Improve user experience ensuring smooth interaction and ease of use.

LANGUAGES

- Arabic: Mother Tongue
- English:Very Good